Mss.B.H76
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to [Sir Henry] Cole, Dec. 31, 1867; 7x4-1/2; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    Kew, A.L.S. 1p. Will call on Thursday to discuss problem.
  - Letter to [Sir Henry] Cole, Jan. 10, 1868; 7x4-1/2; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    Kew, A.L.S. 1p Friendly note
  - Letter to [Sir Henry] Cole, March 20, 1868; 7x4-1/2; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    Kew, A.L.S. 1p.and end. Business.
  - Letter to [William Crawford Williamson?], September 22, 1868; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    Observations on wood.
  - Letter to [Sir John] Kirk, October 18, 1868; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    12 pages.
  - Letter to [Sir Henry] Cole, Jan. 19, 1869; 7x4-1/2; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    A.L.S. 1p.and end. Will call on Tuesday with a friend.
  - Letter to [Sir Henry] Cole, July 20, 1869; 7x4-1/2; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    Kew, A.L.S. 2p. Concerning a publication.
  - Letter to [Henry] Bence Jones, July 30, 1869; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    Regarding the Faraday Memorial Meetings.
  - Letter to [Sir Henry] Cole, Oct. 30, 1869; 7x4-1/2; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    A.L.S. 2p. Business.
  - Letter to [Sir Austen Henry] Layard, November 11, 1869; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    Delighted with the address.
  - Letter to [William Crawford] Williamson, March 20, 1870; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    Regarding points raised in earlier letters from Williamson, applicability to paleontology.
  - Letter to [William Crawford] Williamson, June 18, 1870; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    Regarding Williamson's paper.
  - Letter to Mr. Smith, July 21, 1870; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    Declining an invitation.
  - Letter to Dawson [Hooker], August 13, 1870; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    Recipient Hooker (rather than Turner) as per Richard Drayton, 8/92.
  - Biography of Hooker, September 6, 1871; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    Obtained from Mr. Wallace. Page 5 of author biographies.
  - Letter to [William Crawford] Williamson, February 27, 1872; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
  - Letter to [William Crawford] Williamson, June 21, 1872; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
  - Letter to [Sir Joseph Dalton] Hooker, August 13, 1872; Rivett-Carnac, [H.?]
    Advises Hooker to look at the East Indian Cotton Collection, of possible use to Kew.
  - Letter to [Sir John] Kirk, November 12, 1872; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    2 folded sheets, 8 pages.
  - Letter to Mr. Severn, January 3, 1873; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    Regarding myrtle blossoms.
  - Letter to [Sir Richard] Strachey, Feb. 21, 1873; 6x4; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    Kew, A.L.S. 2p. Would accept the presidencey. Goes to Hastings for holiday.
  - Letter to "Dear Sir", March 10, 1873; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    Accepting the offer of Gardenias.
  - Letter to Mrs. Hutton, April 19, 1873; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    Regarding his wife's health.
  - Letter to [Sir Joseph Dalton] Hooker, September 10, 1873; Grey-Egerton, Philip de Malpas, Sir, 10th bart., 1806-1881
  - Letter to [Robert] Brown, November 12, 1873; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
  - Letter to Dawson [Hooker], November 12, 1873; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
  - Letter to Dr. [Robert] Brown, January 12, 1874; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    Received a copy of Brown's book.
  - Letter to Mr. Smith, August 6, 1874; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    Regarding a drawing.
  - Letter to [William Crawford] Williamson, November 5, 1874; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    Notification of the award of the Royal Medal from the Royal Society.
  - Letter to Dr. [Robert] Brown, December 21, 1874; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    Appreciative of the sympathy.
  - Letter to [Robert] Brown, December 31, 1874; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    Invitation for Tuesday next.
  - Letter to [William Crawford] Williamson, February 8, 1875; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
  - Letter to Dr. Appleton, February 20, 1875; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    Sympathy.
  - Letter to Dawson [Hooker], March 21, 1875; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
  - Letter to "Dear Lady -----, April 4, 1875; 4-1/2x3-3/4; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    Kew, A.L.S. 1p Forwards photograph.
  - Letter to [Sir Richard] Strachey, April 14, 1875; 6-1/4x4; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    Kew, A.L.S. 3p. Plans for travelling to and in France.
  - Letter to [Sir Richard] Strachey, May 8, 1875; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    Kew; A.L.S. 3p. Would like to travel with him in France and suggests route.
  - Letter to [Sir Richard] Strachey, June 1, 1875; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    A.L.S. 2p. Questions the wisdom of manufacturing quinine in India.
  - Letter to [Sir Richard] Strachey, June 4, 1875; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    A.L.S. 3p. Invitation to visit. The "pots" have arrived and he sent some off to Huxley.
  - Letter to Dr. [Robert] Brown, July 8, 1875; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    Regrets inability to meet.
  - Letter to Dr. King, March 13, 1876; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    Regarding Thursday, "a Royal Society night."
  - Letter to "Dear Cooke", March 25, 1876; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    Regarding Rousouch (?) and Boxale (?).
  - Letter to [Sir Richard] Strachey, May 15, 1876; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    List of names.
  - Letter to [Sir Richard] Strachey, May 25, 1876; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    A.L.S. 2p. Lists prominent physicists.
  - Letter to ----, Aug. 18, 1876; 7" x 4 1/2"; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    Royal Gardens, Kew, A.L.S. 3p. Contribution to a hospital.
  - Letter to [Sir Richard] Strachey, Oct. 25, 1876; 7x4-1/2; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    Kew, A.L.S. 4p. Wants a brief note on meteorological research from him.
  - Letter to [Sir Richard] Strachey, January 6, 1877; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    Letter and envelope.
  - Letter to [Sir Richard] Strachey, March 23, 1877; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    A.L.S. 2p. Concerning a post in India.
  - Letter to [Sir Richard] Strachey, April 20, 1877; 7-1/4x4-1/4; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    A.L.S. 4p. Concerning a proposed visit to the U.S. and a tour of it. Refers to Gray.
  - Letter to [Sir Richard] Strachey, May 6, 1877; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    A.L.S. 1p. and add. Concerning an appointment for a friend.
  - Letter to [Sir Richard] Strachey, May 18, 1877; 4-1/2x3-3/4; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    A.L.S. 2p. Invitation to dinner to meet scientific friends from Geneva.
  - Letter to Dr. Trentler, June 4, 1877; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
  - Letter to [Sir Richard] Strachey, June 26, 1877; 4-1-2x3-3/4; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    A.L.S. 1p. Hopes to join him tomorrow.
  - Letter to [Sir Richard] Strachey, Aug. 8, 1877; 8x5; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    San Francisco, A.L.S. 6p. Concerning his travels in the U.S. Geology. Refers to A. Gray.
  - Letter to [Sir Joseph Dalton] Hooker, January 1, 1878; Spottiswoode, William, 1825-1883
    Regarding Hooker's book, an expedition.
  - Letter to ----, May 31, 1878; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    A.L.S. 3p. Approves of the changes. Kew gardens opening date.
  - Letter to ----, October 17, 1878; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
  - Letter to [Sir Richard] Strachey, Nov. 12, 1878; 7-1/4x4-1/4; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    A.L.S. 4p. Is overwhelmed with Royal Society work and botanical problems. States what Kew needs from India.
  - Letter to "My dear Cooke", November 14, 1878; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    Regarding finances.
  - Letter to [Lady Jane Maria Grant] Strachey, Nov. 25, 1878; 6x4; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    A.L.S. 3p. Thanks for the Check. Comments on her husband.
  - Letter to Sir Joseph [Dalton Hooker], December 15, 1878; Siemens, Charles William, Sir, 1823-1883
    Regarding Royal Society subscription.
  - Letter to "My dear Aunt", March 3, 1879; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
  - Letter to Sir William [Jenner], October 23(?), 1879; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    Introduction of H. J. Ryder. Includes envelope and Ryder's card.
  - Letter to [Šir Richard] Strachey, Dec. 20, 1879; 7x4-1/2; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    A.L.S. 4p. Identification of his Indian botanical specimens.
  - Letter to [Sir Richard] Strachey, Jan. 17, 1880; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    A.L.S. 8p. Concerning various collections of natural history material to be made in India.
  - Letter to Mr. Browne, February 18, 1880; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    Manufacturing and material details.
  - Letter to [Sir Richard] Strachey, Feb. 22, 1880; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    A.L.S. 3p. Will be glad to get the Indian specimens all done.
  - Letter to [Sir Richard] Strachey, February 28, 1880; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    Museum business.
  - Letter to Mr. Severn, April 27, 1880; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    Arrangements to meet Severn's mother.
  - Letter to [Sir Richard] Strachey, May 17, 1880; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
  - Letter to [William Crawford] Williamson, June 10, 1880; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    Regarding nomenclature.
  - Letter to [Sir Richard] S[trachey], Sept. 15, 1880; 4-1/2x3-1/2; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    A.L.S. 4p. The Grays arrive tomorrow and he is invited to visit with them. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Sir Joseph Dalton] Hooker, October 11, 1880; Franks, Augustus Wollaston, Sir, 1826-1897
    Accepts Hooker's invitation.
  - Letter to [Sir Joseph Dalton] Hooker, January 1, 1881; Strachey, Richard, Sir, 1817-1908
    Arrangements to send gardner to Kew to "pick up anything suitable."
  - Letter to [Sir Joseph Dalton] Hooker, January 5, 1881; Franks, Augustus Wollaston, Sir, 1826-1897
    Regarding a visit to Kew; hopes to meet "your Chinese friend."
  - Letter to [Sir Richard] Strachey, May 17, 1882; 7x4-1/2; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    A.L.S. 3p. Division of natural history material from India.
  - Letter to [William Crawford] Williamson, June 7, 1883; Half penny post card.; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
  - Letter to [William Crawford] Williamson, June 16, 1883; Half penny post card.; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
  - Letter to [William Crawford] Williamson, July 19, 1883; Half penny post card.
  - Letter to Dawson [Hooker], August 31, 1883; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    Recipient Hooker (rather than Turner) per Richard Drayton, 8/92.
  - Letter to [Sir Richard] Strachey, July 22, 1884; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    A.L.S. 2p. "Huxley, Flower, Lubbock and myself" are working on the Affghan [sic] settlement. Comments on a man needing a post.
  - Letter to----, Jan. 14, 1885; 4 1/2" x 3 1/2"; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    Royal Gardens, Kew, (?) A.L.S. 2p. Suggests that he apply to Mr. F.O. Bower for aid.
  - Letter to Bewicke, July 9, 1885; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    Regarding a paper.
  - Letter to [Sir Richard] Strachey, 1885; 7x4-1/2; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    A.L.S. 1p. Retires from Kew "on the 30th."
  - Letter to Sir Joseph [Dalton Hooker], July 11, 1887; Lyell, Charles, Sir, 1797-1875
    Regarding botanical names.
  - Letter to [Lady Jane Maria Grant] Strachey, March 21, 1888; 7x4-1/2; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    A.L.S. 1p. and add. Thanks her husband for his help. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to "My dear Aunt", April 12, 1889; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    Regarding a request for a picture, an invitation, and family updates.
  - Letter to "My dear Aunt", April 18, 1889; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    Regarding travel, children's education.
  - Letter to "My dear Aunt", April 18, 1889; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    Family updates.
  - Letter to "Aunt", April 21, 1889; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    Regarding picture to be sent.
  - Letter to "My dear Aunt", June 2, 1889; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    Regarding the return of the picture; Australian expedition.
  - Letter to [William Crawford] Williamson, July 17, 1889; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    Regarding flora, fossils.
  - Letter to "My dear Aunt Effie", September 19, 1889; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    Regarding picture, family updates.
  - Letter to [Sir Richard] Strachey, Dec. 26, 1898; 7x4-1/2; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    A.L.S. 2p. Comments on books on Africa.
  - Letter to Woodward, December 15, 1890; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
  - Letter to Dawson [Hooker], May 1, 1893; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    REcipient Hooker per Richard Drayton 8/92.
  - Letter to [Sir Clements] Markham, March 29, 1895; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    Regarding meeting.
  - Letter to Woodward, September 22, 1897; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
  - Letter to Mr. Melvile, November 24, 1897; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    Separated Materials note
    Purchased with Letters of scientists.
  - Letter to "My dear Cousin", April 22, 1901; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
  - Letter to Woodward, August 2, 1902; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
  - Letter to "Cousin Polly", May 16, 1904; Includes envelope addressed to Woodward.; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    Regarding a photograph of Dawson Turner.
  - Letter to "Cousin Polly", July 2, 1905; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    Personal news.
  - Letter to Woodward, September 28, 1905; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    Regarding Tibet.
  - Letter to "My dear Cousin", June 14, 1907; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    Personal news, health.
  - Letter to Woodward, November 28, 1908; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
  - Letter to Mrs. Woodward, November 28, 1910; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
  - Letter to [Sir Joseph Dalton?] Hooker, January 27, undated; Burton, Decimus, 1800-1881
    Regarding a package.
  - Letter to [Sir Richard] Strachey, April 19, undated; 7-1/2x4-1/2; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    Kew, A.L.S. 2p. Asks him to take chair. Business.
  - Letter to [Sir Joseph Dalton] Hooker, April 23, undated; Reeve, Henry, 1813-1895
    Regrets he was too unwell to attend the Royal Society the previous evening.
  - Letter to [Sir Joseph Dalton] Hooker, May 21, undated; Ferguson, William, 1820-1887
    Plans to be at the Atheneum.
  - Letter to [Sir Richard] Strachey, July 31, undated; 8x5; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    A.L.S. 2p. Encloses Spottiswoode's answer to Galton, etc. Friendly letter. Compliments him on his publication.
  - Letter to [Sir Joseph Dalton?] Hooker, November 25, undated; Ramsay, A. C., (Andrew Crombie), 1814-1891
    Recommends contacting Reeks to ask about Ball, about whom Ramsay knows nothing.
  - Letter to [Sir Joseph Dalton?] Hooker, Monday, undated; Candolle, Alphonse de, 1806-1893
    In French. Regarding plans to meet.
  - Letter to [Sir H. Ellis?], Monday, undated; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    Regarding plants.
  - Letter to [Lovell Augustus Reeve?], Monday, undated; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
  - Letter to Dawson [Hooker], Tuesday, undated; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    Recipient Hooker (rather than Turner) as per Richard Drayton 8/92.
  - Letter to Dawson [Hooker], Wednesday, undated; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
  - Letter to [Eliza] Meteyard, Thursday, undated; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    Regarding requests to Mr. Wedgwood, books, photography.
  - Letter to Mrs. Stokes, Thursday, undated; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
  - Letter to [Sir John William] Lubbock, Friday, undated; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
  - Letter to [Lovell Augusts Reeve?], Friday, undated; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
  - Letter to [Sir Richard] Strachey, Friday, undated; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
  - Letter to [Sir Richard] Strachey, Saturday, undated; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
  - Letter to [Lovell Augustus Reeve?], undated; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
  - Letter to [Sir Richard] Strachey, undated; 7x4-1/2; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    Friday. A.L.S. 4p. In pencil. Humidity. Refers to Tyndall. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Sir Richard Strachey], undated; 5-1/2x3-1/2; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    Kew Saturday. A.L.S. 1p. Archibald Smith would like to visit.
  - Envelopes, June 10, 1907; undated
    2 envelopes. June 10, 1907; undated.
  - Notebook, 1784-1791, undated; 5 1/4" x 3"; Hopkinson, Francis, 1737-1791
    A.D. 5 leaves paper bd. Mentions APS bond for £300, Feb. 20, 1784.
  - Poems, undated; Hopkinson, Francis, 1737-1791
    A.D.S. 11 items, with one duplicate copy. Various sizes. (for titles, see table of contents) Now 12 items, since one leaf was divided.